

Praveen Kumar Rajendran

GRADUATE RESEARCHER · COMPUTER VISION · KAIST

🛘 (+82) 10-7262-1561 🔻 aravindhanpraveen19@gmail.com 🥀 Portfolio 🗓 GitHub 🛅 LinkedIn 💆 Twitter 📢 Medium

Scholar

♥ Daejeon, S.Korea

Summary_

I am a Graduate student researcher in Vehicular Intelligence Lab at Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology. Currently pursuing M.S. in Future Vehicle Program, advised by *Prof. Dongsoo Har.* My research interests include deep learning, 3D computer vision and autonomous driving. Before joining KAIST, I worked with SL Lumax and SL Corporation as Automotive Software Engineer. I love cycling. I enjoy videos of 3Blue1Brown and Veritasium.

Work Experience ___



KAIST - Vehicullar Intelligence Lab GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCHER

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2023

- · Worked on accident prevention ADAS system using OpenCV, Deep learning, Class activation maps, and Segmentation
- Worked with ROS for the Multi-LiDAR parking robot project.
- Collaborated on PMD path planning and trajectory prediction in heterogeneous traffic.
- Achieved SoTA on relative camera pose estimation problems with deep learning and published at ECCV-Workshop 2022
- Working on Domain Adaption. Exploring Point Cloud Registration/Analysis for further research.

Chennai, India & Gyeongsan,

S.Korea

Nov. 2018 - Feb. 2021

SL Lumax & SL Corporation · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Part Leader for the Indian software verification Team at SL Corporation.
- Responsible for Software Unit testing (APP+BSP) of Head Lamps LED Driver Module (LDM), Electronic Control Unit (ECU), Integrated Lamp
 Control Unit (ILCU), Door side Object Detection, Camera Monitoring System, Intelligent battery management system and E-shifters.
- Performed more than 250+ software unit/integration testing projects with the team.
- Professional working knowledge on CodeScroll Controller tester for Unit/Integration testing, VBA, VectorCAST and Source code analysis.
- · Preparing test Specification and establishing Traceability between Design requirements and test Specification.
- · Interaction with Software Design Engineers, and analyze the issues to fast pace the development and test closure activities.
- Sent to HQ to closely work with developers and test engineers of various countries such as the USA, China, Korea and India.
- Certified ISTQB CTFL by Korean Software Testing Qualifications Board.

GRADUATE ENGINEERING TRAINEE - SOFTWARE

Nov. 2017 - Oct. 2018

- Responsible for SiL Unit Test of LED Driver Module (LDM). In-depth Boundary-Value analysis for safety critical systems (bitwise/absolute)
- Software Verification and validation(QA Static Analysis, Codescroll Controlled Tester Dynamic Analysis).
- Familiarity with the Embedded C analysis, scripting, Cadence PCB Training

Chennai, India

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2016

- Aerobotix · Robotics and Embedded Systems Intern
- Trained to work with Arduino UNO, Electronics, Sensors, Actuators and Programming microcontrollers.
 Built different robotics applications such as line follower, RC boat, RC hovercraft.
- Hands-on experience on Bluetooth and various modules for navigation.

Education ___



KAIST (World Ranking 20) · M.S. IN FUTURE VEHICLE PROGRAM

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2023

- **GPA:** $3.9/4.3 \approx 95.55\%$
- **Subjects:** Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Autonomous Vehicle Systems, Intelligent Transportation Systems, WL Analysis, Operating Systems, Scientific Writing

Udacity

Udacity · Self Driving Car Nanodegree

Remote July 2021

- Term-1 Projects: Lane detection, Advanced Lane detection, Traffic sign classfier, Behavioral cloning, EKF
- **Term-2 Projects:** Particle filter, Highway driving, PID Controller, System Integration
- Project details and curriculum can be found here

NOVEMBER 6, 2022



- **GPA:** $8.1/10 \approx 81\%$
- **Subjects:** Engineering Mathematics, Engineering Graphics, Embedded Systems, Control Systems, Object-Oriented Programming, Circuit Theory, Electrical Machines, Power Electronics

Skills___

Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Robotics, Camera Calibration, Embedded Systems, Software Testing,

Multi-view Geometry, 3D Reconstruction, Computational Photography, Visual Localization, Generative adversarial networks

Programming Python, C, MATLAB, C++

Frameworks & Tools

Git, PyTorch, TensorFlow, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Codescroll Controller Tester, VectorCAST, Pandas, OpenCV, Keras, Matplotlib,

openmm, ROS, Linux, VSCode, Jupyter, Anaconda, Docker, LaTeX

Languages Tamil(Native), English(Professional), Korean(TOPIK 1)

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2022	Acceptance , Oxford Machine Learning Summer School, University of Oxford & Al for Global Goals	Oxford, U.K
2019	Recepient, KAIST full funding scholarship for Master's program in Future Vehicle	Daejeon, S.Korea
2019	Recepient , Recipient of Udacity Technology Scholarship powered by Bertelsmann for Al Track - Phase 1	Remote
2019	Award, Korea cycling road grand slam given by K-Water for completion of cycling route of 1837KM	Seoul, S.Korea
2019	Position , Selected for a leadership position of Electronics team of 24 people in SL Corporation.	Gyeongsan, S.Korea

DOMESTIC

-	2017	Go Green Award , for making an efficient solar vehicle for Asia's largest solar vehicle competition with Team	Bhimavaram, India
2017	2017	AATHIRI, ESVC - 2017	Dillinavarani, maia
	0016	Silver Prize, for the Robotics event of PATHFINDER(Line Follower) in the national level technical symposium	Chennai. India
2016	2010	VISION organized by Anna University	Chennai, maia
	School Topper, Higher secondary public examination	Mayiladuthurai,	
2013	2013	School topper, frigher secondary public examination	India

Publications

RelMobNet: End-to-end relative camera pose estimation using a robust two-stage training

ECCV Workshop

Praveen Kumar Rajendran, Sumit Mishra, Luiz Felipe Vecchietti, Dongsoo Har

2022

Sensing accident-prone features in urban scenes for proactive driving and accident prevention

IEEE ITS (IF:9.5) - Under Review

Sumit Mishra, **Praveen Kumar Rajendran**, Luiz Felipe Vecchietti, Dongsoo Har

2022

Socially acceptable route planning and trajectory behavior analysis of personal mobility device for mobility management with improved sensing

RiTA

SUMIT MISHRA, PRAVEEN KUMAR RAJENDRAN, DONGSOO HAR

2021

Projects_

Capstone Project: Relative Camera Pose Estimation with Deep Learning

Daejeon, S.Korea

CS570 ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE AND MACHINE LEARNING

Dec. 2021

· Achieved SoTA accuracy in Cambridge landmark dataset in comparison to previous deep learning approaches.

Capstone Project: ADAS for accident Prevention

Daejeon, S.Korea

PD803 Perception for autonomous and connected vehicles

Dec. 2021

• a cost-effective system that has the potential to improve driver attention to accident cues while avoiding slap-dash behaviour at accident hotspot locations. Worked with pandas, PyTorch mmsegmentation, class activation maps and matplotlib extensively.

Capstone Project: End-to-End Autonomous Driving

Daejeon, S.Korea

PD551 FUNDAMENTALS OF VEHICLE ELECTRIC SYSTEMS

Dec. 2021

· End-to-End autonomous driving using imitation learning (Inspired by the famous NVIDIA paper) with the data collected from CARLA

Course Projects: Projective Geometry & Computational Photogrammetry

Daejeon, S.Korea

PD551 PERCEPTION FOR AUTONOMOUS AND CONNECTED VEHICLES

Dec. 2021

• Camera Calibration, 3D Reconstruction in MATLAB

Course Projects: CNN Analysis, Regularizations, Sequential modelling

Daejeon, S.Korea

Al502 DEEP LEARNING

Jun. 2021

Deep Convolution Architecture Analysis with multiple optimizers and regularization techniques. Sequential modelling with LSTMs, Transformers, BERT for extractive Q&A.

Course Projects: Construction of Building Blocks of OS with xv6

Daejeon, S.Korea

EE415 OPERATING SYSTEM

Jun. 2021

Feb. 2017

• Kernel Threading, Process Scheduler, Nullptr Dereferences and Shared Page Handler, Filesystem Optimization (for small files)

Electric solar vehicle Chennai, India

FSVC

• Made a Conventional Solar vehicle from scratch at low cost with a team of twenty five members for the Asia's largest solar vehicle championship. Secured 21st place out of 150 teams from all over asia. I was the vice captain of the team. Along with a MPPT Controller project at BHEL advised by Dr. Kevin ark kumar.

Robotic Arm Chennai, India

PROJECT AT **AEROBOTIX**Mar. 2016

• With the help of flex sensors, various motors and 3D printed objects made a robotic arm which will perform all the actions done by human hand.

Certifications

Aug. 2022 Oxford Machine Learning Summer School 2022, OxML 2022	University of Oxford
Apr. 2022 Probabilistic Graphical Models - Representation , Stanford University	Coursera
Jul. 2021 Self-Driving Car Engineer , Nanodegree Program	Udacity
Mar. 2020 TensorFlow - Data and Deployment Specialization, deeplearning.ai	Coursera
Jan. 2020 Deep Learning Specialization , deeplearning.ai	Coursera
Dec. 2019 Bertelsmann Technology Scholarship Phase 1, Al Track	Udacity
Dec. 2019 TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate, deepleaning.ai	Coursera
Nov. 2019 Machine Learning, Stanford University	Coursera
Oct. 2019 ISTQB CTFL, Certification	KSTQB
Feb. 2017 Student Industry Project , Solar Power Controller	BHEL, Trichy
May. 2015 Inplant Training, Power Stability Control	SAIL, Salem

Volunteering_

IEEE Sensors Journal, ICRA 2023

REVIEWERPRESENT

Aerobotix

Workshop Co-ordinator

Jan. 2016 - Oct. 2016

References_

Prof. Dongsoo Har

Associate Professor

KAIST

Cho Chun Shik Graduate School of Mobility

♠ Daejeon, S.Korea

dshar@kaist.ac.kr

Dr. Luiz Felipe Vecchietti

Senior Researcher

Data Science Group - IBS

Center for Mathematical & Computational Sciences

Daejeon, S.Korea

■ Ifelipesv@ibs.re.kr